<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life.CEO</title>
    <description>Exploring the many dimensions of life.
</description>
    <link>http://www.life.ceo/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.life.ceo/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 16:41:47 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 16:41:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Slack worth it?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/slack-logo.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend recently sent me information on the skyrocketing valuation of Slack.  As I began to prepare this post, I realized that I didn’t know exactly where to find the information. Was it a link on text messages?  Was it via evernote or a direct message on twitter?  Was it sent as a PDF through email?  Slack tries to solve the problem of communication fragmentation.  Slack seeks to “be a platform for team communication: everything in one place, instantly searchable, available wherever you go.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:slack2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:slack2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;”  Essentially, slack seeks to replace text messages, emails, alerts, and notifications create a singular funnel of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/slack-why.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Douglas Macmillian writing for the Wall Street Journal writes about the phenomenal growth and valuation of slack.  He writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In an era of soaring valuations for tech startups, Slack has emerged as one of the industry’s most rapidly-appreciating assets a little more than a year after launching its first product. The startup has more than doubled in value since five months ago, when investors valued Slack at $1.12 billion, and now ranks among the world’s most valuable venture-backed developers of software for businesses. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:slack&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:slack&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this wild valuation another case of a champagne high? Probably.  Although this is an important and interesting question, I’d like to focus on whether this app is worthwhile.  Regardless of the speculative value of the company, I think that Slack platform has enormous benefits and offers the potential to solve many problems.  To summarize, here are few of the key benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Slack has a myriad of integrations with other software and tools.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/integrations&quot;&gt;official integrations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/community&quot;&gt;unofficial integrations&lt;/a&gt; that are built by the rapidly growing community. These integrations help pull information from a variety of services into the slack ecosystem. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/slack-integrations.png&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Email was once cool, but now it is a burden.  Instead of hundreds of people sending a hodgepodge of unfiltered and unsorted into one email account, slack enables users to create channels to corral conversations into discreet containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) All of conversations and information is archived and can be searched.  It saves you the trouble of trying to figure out where you put that link or article that a colleague or friend sent to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Slack works on just about every modern device and operating system.  If you want to use slack on the road, you will have to retire your Palm Pilot or flip phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is something enticing using a clean and well designed platform.  We’ll have to wait to see if Slack helps make sense of the digital explosions in our lives or if it gets tossed aside in the digital dustbin.  Slack is a disruptive technology that fixes some of the problems of how people communicate with one another.  For now, I’m going to Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:slack2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://slack.com &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:slack2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:slack&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2015/03/26/slacks-valuation-more-than-doubles-to-2-8-billion-in-five-months/ &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:slack&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.life.ceo/2015/04/03/slack-worth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.life.ceo/2015/04/03/slack-worth.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll Snippets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/jekyll-snippets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/jekyll-snippets.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Install Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;install-jekyll&quot;&gt;Install Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gem install Jekyll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;move-into-the-folder-that-you-want-to-install-jekyll&quot;&gt;Move into the folder that you want to install Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open up the terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you aren’t a terminal jockey, then do the the following:
 type cd and then drag the folder on to the terminal.  Hit return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-your-new-site&quot;&gt;Create your new site&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in my case, jekyll new lifeceo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;fire-up-your-new-site&quot;&gt;Fire up your new site!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd into lifeceo
http://127.0.0.1:4000/&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/install-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/install-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Deploy your Jekyll Site</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;buy-a-doman&quot;&gt;Buy a Doman&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have bought domain names through several companies.  I haven’t used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.godaddy.com&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt; for several years, but they used to be notorious for a confusing checkout process in which they were notorious for upselling products.  In contrast, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hover.com&quot;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; proviides a smooth and uncluttered way to search for a domain and to purchase it.  I highly recommend Hover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;configure-the-dns&quot;&gt;Configure the DNS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.netlify.com/custom_domains/&quot;&gt;Netlify documentation&lt;/a&gt;, but here is the relavent snippet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Create a CNAME that will &quot;alias&quot; your site to www.netlify.com. If your domain is example.com, you might alias www.example.com to www.netlify.com.
* Create an A record for the raw domain (example.com) pointing to 198.61.251.14
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/deploy-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.life.ceo/2015/03/28/deploy-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
