<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Life.Ceo</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.life.ceo/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo" />
<updated>2015-04-04T19:58:14-07:00</updated>
<id>http://www.life.ceo/</id>
<author>
  <name>Steve Scott</name>
  <uri>http://www.life.ceo/</uri>
  
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Passwords: Simple or Complex]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo/password-manager/" />
  <id>http://www.life.ceo/password-manager</id>
  <published>2015-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Steve Scott</name>
    <uri>http://www.life.ceo</uri>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/password2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week there was a bit of an uproar over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tdcanadatrust.com/products-services/banking/index-banking.jsp&quot;&gt;TD Canada Trust&lt;/a&gt; who disabled the ability for its users to copy/paste passwords into their iOS app.  The controversy got into full swing when in response to a customer question, TD Canada Trust posted this on twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”. . . your password should be committed to memory rather than using a password mgr” –&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/roustem/status/578909191533944832&quot;&gt;via Twitter&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgileBits, the makers of the awesome &lt;strong&gt;1Password&lt;/strong&gt; app wrote a fantastic open letter which included the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Using long, random, and unique passwords is the best defense that we, your users, have against attackers. This advice is true for every site we have to sign in to these days … and believe me, we sign in to a lot more than just our financial sites. Keeping 100 or so strong and unique passwords memorized is not only a silly suggestion, it’s nearly impossible for all but the most savant-ish of us. Password managers help us increase our security by remembering these unique passwords for us, keeping them stored securely, and filling them in on websites so we don’t have to. – Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.agilebits.com/2015/03/23/an-open-letter-to-banks/&quot;&gt;1Password Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, TD Canada Trust relented and re-enabled copy/paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given a choice between a simple memorized password that is typically used at multiple sites or a complex password that is unique at every website, I’ll recommend the password manager &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/password.png&quot; alt=&quot;Password&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/password-manager/&quot;&gt;Passwords: Simple or Complex&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Steve Scott at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo&quot;&gt;Life.Ceo&lt;/a&gt; on April 03, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fantastical 2 Review]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo/fantastical-2/" />
  <id>http://www.life.ceo/fantastical-2</id>
  <published>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Steve Scott</name>
    <uri>http://www.life.ceo</uri>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been a long-time user of the Fantastical Menu Bar app and Fantastical for the iPhone.  It always provided a quick scan of the day and helped me to check to see the next upcoming appointment.  If you are unfamiliar with Fantastical for the iPhone, check out Steve Owen’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-calendar-app-iphone/&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; over at the Sweet Setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.busymac.com/busycal/&quot;&gt;BusyCal&lt;/a&gt;– until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fantastical 2 has just changed the osx calendar app field with a beautiful application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the features that make this worth purchasing or at least giving it a shot with the 14 day demo which you can download &lt;a href=&quot;http://flexibits.com/fantastical&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/fantastical2-mac-miniwindow.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; class=&quot;image-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use natural lanugage such as &lt;strong&gt;take car to shop at 1pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fantastical 2 has sweated every pixel to create a beautiful and clear design. Federico Viticci writes: “Its information-rich display is based on a rigorous attention to visual cues and Flexibits have outdone themselves in translating the iOS experience to navigation that feels at home on OS X.”– &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macstories.net/reviews/fantastical-2-for-mac-review-reinvented/&quot;&gt;MacStories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Calendar Sets” which help you to organize your calendars.  You can create a calendar set for home, one for work, and one for seeing family events.  Instead of toggling individual calendars on or off, you can quick jump to the set for the proper context. Even better, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geo-fence&quot;&gt;geofencing&lt;/a&gt; you can automatically switch calendars based on your location.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fantastical 2 improves on the “Mini Window” which enables you to quickly scan through your appointments without opening the app.  You can now pull the window away from the menu bar and have it float wherever you want.  This is helpful when you are trying to consult your calendar while working in another app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/fantastical-2/&quot;&gt;Fantastical 2 Review&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Steve Scott at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo&quot;&gt;Life.Ceo&lt;/a&gt; on April 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Become an Apple Affiliate]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo/apple-affilate/" />
  <id>http://www.life.ceo/apple-affilate</id>
  <published>2015-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Steve Scott</name>
    <uri>http://www.life.ceo</uri>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Have you ever recommended an iphone app to someone? Of course you have!  Most of us technology mavens take great delight in helping someone solve a problem by using our &lt;em&gt;app de jour&lt;/em&gt;.  Gabe Wetherhead of MacDrifter provides a compelling reason to become an Apple Affiliate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let me start by saying that even if you don’t have a blog, you should create an affiliate account and generate affiliate links. You’ll make some money back on your purchases you make with it. You will also make a few cents when you share it on Twitter and people buy something with the link. No one gets hurt and you get some motivation to share interesting stuff.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macdrifter.com/2015/03/blink-for-ios.html&quot;&gt;via Macdrifter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to linking to apps, you can earn commissions by linking to books, music videos, music, movies, and TV shows.  So, how do you get this done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.phgconsole.performancehorizon.com/login/itunes/en_us&quot;&gt;Apple Affiliate Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill out the brief application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait to be confirmed as an affiliate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do what you normally do (recommend, don’t push!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/apple-affilate/&quot;&gt;Become an Apple Affiliate&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Steve Scott at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo&quot;&gt;Life.Ceo&lt;/a&gt; on April 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Won't Press Amazon Dash Button ]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo/amazon-dash/" />
  <id>http://www.life.ceo/amazon-dash</id>
  <published>2015-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Steve Scott</name>
    <uri>http://www.life.ceo</uri>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Amazon has just released a new way to buy things called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/oc/dash-button/&quot;&gt;Amazon Dash&lt;/a&gt;.  When you sign up for the program you identify products that you use and your receive a special “Dash Button.” You press this button when you want to re-supply your inventory and amazon will begin to process the order.  While this is an interesting concept, it seems unnecessary.  Do people really want to have dash buttons all around the house, office, and yard?  It is already too easy to buy things on Amazon.  The Dash Button feels frivolous and wasteful.  Why not just take out your cell phone and scan the barcode and hit order?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the product is ripe for a Saturday Night Live parody.  I can picture a beautiful actress sitting on the toilet frantically pushing the dash button because she has run out of toilet paper only to have the UPS guy walk into the bathroom with a fresh roll of toilet paper. Honestly, if I saw this post on April 1st, I would think this was a good hearted joke.  Do you remember the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/b?node=8037720011&quot;&gt;Amazon delivery drones&lt;/a&gt;?  Amazon still claims this is a real product delivery system, but that is a conversation for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/amazon-dash2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/amazon-dash/&quot;&gt;Won&#39;t Press Amazon Dash Button &lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Steve Scott at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo&quot;&gt;Life.Ceo&lt;/a&gt; on March 31, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Slack worth it?]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.life.ceo/slack-worth/" />
  <id>http://www.life.ceo/slack-worth</id>
  <published>2015-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Steve Scott</name>
    <uri>http://www.life.ceo</uri>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;A friend recently sent me information on the skyrocketing valuation of Slack.  As I began to prepare this post, I realized that I didn’t know exactly where to find the information. Was it a link on text messages?  Was it sent via evernote or a direct message on twitter?  Was it sent as a PDF through email?  Slack tries to solve the problem of communication fragmentation.  Slack seeks to “be a platform for team communication: everything in one place, instantly searchable, available wherever you go.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:slack2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:slack2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;”  Essentially, Slack seeks to replace text messages, emails, alerts, and notifications create a singular funnel of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/slack-why.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Douglas Macmillian, writing for the Wall Street Journal blog on March 26, 2015, writes about the phenomenal growth and valuation of slack.  He writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In an era of soaring valuations for tech startups, Slack has emerged as one of the industry’s most rapidly-appreciating assets a little more than a year after launching its first product. The startup has more than doubled in value since five months ago, when investors valued Slack at $1.12 billion, and now ranks among the world’s most valuable venture-backed developers of software for businesses. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:slack&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:slack&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this wild valuation another case of a champagne high? Probably.  Although this is an important and interesting question, I’d like to focus on whether this app is worthwhile.  Regardless of the speculative value of the company, I think that Slack platform has enormous benefits and offers the potential to solve many problems.  To summarize, here are few of the key benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Slack has a myriad of integrations with other software and tools.  There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.com/integrations&quot;&gt;official integrations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://api.slack.com/community&quot;&gt;unofficial integrations&lt;/a&gt; that are built by the rapidly growing community. These integrations help pull information from a variety of services into the Slack ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Email was once cool, but it is now a burden.  Instead of hundreds of people sending a hodgepodge of unfiltered and unsorted email into one account, Slack enables users to create channels to corral conversations into discreet containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) All of the conversations and information are archived and can be searched.  It saves you the trouble of trying to figure out where you put that link or article that a colleague or friend sent to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/images/slack-integrations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Slack works on just about every modern device and operating system.  If you want to use Slack on the road, you will have to retire your Palm Pilot or flip phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is something enticing about using a clean and well designed platform.  We will have to wait to see if Slack helps make sense of the digital explosions in our lives or if it gets tossed aside in the digital dustbin.  For me, the bottom line is that Slack fixes some of the problems of how people communicate with one another. For now, I’m going to use Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:slack2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://slack.com &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:slack2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:slack&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2015/03/26/slacks-valuation-more-than-doubles-to-2-8-billion-in-five-months/ &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:slack&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo/slack-worth/&quot;&gt;Is Slack worth it?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Steve Scott at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.life.ceo&quot;&gt;Life.Ceo&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
